

Naod Dereje

Computer Engineering Student



Professional Summary

Engineering student currently finalizing B.A.Sc diploma in Computer Engineering and prepared to contribute abilities to a Software Development role while further developing acquired skills and gaining real-world experience. Highly organized, responsible and well-versed in [Software]. Positively impact [Type] operations with top-notch communication and critical thinking skills.



Side Projects

Holographic TV Innovation Project

 Used CAD modeling software to perform stress analysis on a mechanism that retracts folding panels to display holographic content as a form of technological innovation. Minimal work was done with Printed Circuit Boards (PCBs) to create a more realistic model of the TV but was later scraped due to technical feasibility at the time.

GuessMaster

 Used Android Studio and cumulative knowledge of OOP to build a guessing game based on a database of entities.

Contacts Applet

 Used JavaFX to Create applet that writes to a JSON data file and stores contact information for the user.

Pong/Table Tennis Program

 Used the JavaFX library to create a simulation of a table tennis match like the classic game PONG.
This method used basic trigonometry and other math to create and accurate 2D simulation of the game.

Personal Website (Work in Progress)

 Combined knowledge of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create a stunning website. Custom JS Animations also used. Finalized version will be hosted on github.



Work Experience

2019-09 -2020-04

Control Systems Engineer

Queen's Hyperloop Design Team, Kingston, Ontario

- Technically supported project planning for development of the 2019 Hyperloop pod and implementation of proposals and solutions to address hardware and software problems regarding the previous years competition
- Maximized proficiency in C and C++ to prepare and present tentative designs and effectively support cross-functionally with the networking subteams



Address

Toronto, ON, M9W6Z3

Phone

(647) 973-3438

E-mail

naod07@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in /naod-d-4495a8105

www

https://github.com/naodder eie



~

C++

Java

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Solid Edge

Autodesk Inventor

....

0000

0000

0000

0000

00000

....

AutoDesk Eagle

••••

KiCad

MATLAB

••••

Excel

....

PowerPoint

•••••

Word

0000

Git

0000

Android Studio

....

2020-04

2019-09 - Software Engineer

Queens VEX U Robotics, Kingston, Ontario

- · Contributed to PROS codebase used in deployment of software on the V5 brain designed by VEX
- · Outlined and programmed routines and parameters for different robotic systems
- · Worked on the algorithm associated with the position tracking of the robot, as well as helping to maintain a proper workflow in the main C codebase

2018-08

2018-06 - Customer Marketing Associate

Scotiabank Theatre Toronto, Toronto, ON

- · Part of a team of four or five workers that provided guests with the experience of Virtual Reality(VR)
- · Accommodated private bookings for up to 30 guests at a time
- · Marketed the IMAX VR® experience to guests at Scotiabank Theatre Toronto
- · Investigated malfunctions of the VR equipment, tracking issues to discover root causes and possible corrective measures

2017-10

2017-04 - Customer Service Representative

Parkway Corporation, Toronto, ON

- · Cultivated customer loyalty, promoted repeat customers and improved sales.
- · Fielded oustomer questions regarding available hours of operation, parking rates, current prices and upcoming company changes.
- · Answered customer telephone calls promptly to avoid on-hold wait times.



Education

2018-09 -Current

Bachelor of Applied Science: Computer Engineering

Queen's University - Kingston

GPA: 3.010/4.00

- Part of Innovation and Entrepreneurship stream
- · Coursework in Data Structures, OOP, Discrete Mathematics, and Computer Architecture
- · Member of Living Learning Community in Residence
- · Director at Queen's Software Development Club
- · Awarded Churchill First Generation Admission

2018-06

2014-09 - High School Diploma

Crescent School - Toronto

- · Coursework in AP Physics, AP Chemistry and AP Computer Science
- · Graduated with 85% grade average
- Awarded Ontario Scholar distinction
- · Member of Student Technology Assistance Council
- · Member of Chemistry Education Research Club



(2) Interests

- Sports Science
- Sports Analytics: NBA and NCAA
- Rhythm Theory
- Rap: Rhyme Schemes and Lyrical Flow